{
   "title": "Computer Architecture and AI",
   "category": "Technology",
   "level0": [
      {
         "prompt": "Who developed the basic architecture of computers?",
         "options": [
            "Blaise Pascal",
            "Charles Babbage",
            "John Von Neuman",
            "None of the above"
         ],
         "correctAnswer": 2,
         "level": 0
      },
      {
         "prompt": "Which of the following allows simultaneous write and read operations?",
         "options": ["ROM", "EPROM", "RAM", "VROM"],
         "correctAnswer": 2,
         "level": 0
      },
      {
         "prompt": "Which of the following is not considered as a peripheral device?",
         "options": ["CPU", "Keyboard", "Monitor", "All of the above"],
         "correctAnswer": 0,
         "level": 0
      },
      {
         "prompt": "Which of the following computer memory is the fastest?",
         "options": ["Register", "Harddisk", "RAM", "None of the above"],
         "correctAnswer": 0,
         "level": 0
      },
      {
         "prompt": "Which of the following operations is/are performed by the ALU?",
         "options": [
            "Data Manipulation",
            "Exponential",
            "Squareroot",
            "All of the above"
         ],
         "correctAnswer": 3,
         "level": 0
      },
      {
         "prompt": "Which of the following formats is used to store data?",
         "options": ["Decimal", "Octal", "BCD", "Hexadecimal"],
         "correctAnswer": 2,
         "level": 0
      },
      {
         "prompt": "Which of the following memory of the computer is used to speed up the computer processing?",
         "options": ["Cache memory", "RAM", "ROM", "None of the above"],
         "correctAnswer": 0,
         "level": 0
      },
      {
         "prompt": "Computer address bus is - ?",
         "options": [
            "Multidirectional",
            "Bidirectional",
            "Unidirectional",
            "None of the above"
         ],
         "correctAnswer": 2,
         "level": 0
      },
      {
         "prompt": "Which of the following circuits is used to store one bit of data?",
         "options": ["Flip Flop", "Decoder", "Encoder", "Register"],
         "correctAnswer": 0,
         "level": 0
      },
      {
         "prompt": "Which of the following is a way in which the components of a computer are connected to each other?",
         "options": [
            "Computer parts",
            "Computer architecture",
            "Computer Hardware",
            "None of the above"
         ],
         "correctAnswer": 1,
         "level": 0
      },
      {
         "prompt": "Which of the following circuits converts the binary data into a decimal?",
         "options": ["Decoder", "Encoder", "Code converter", "Multiplexer"],
         "correctAnswer": 2,
         "level": 0
      },
      {
         "prompt": "The address in the main memory is known as...",
         "options": [
            "Logical address",
            "Physical address",
            "Memory address",
            "None of the above"
         ],
         "correctAnswer": 1,
         "level": 0
      },
      {
         "prompt": "Subtraction in computers is carried out by...",
         "options": [
            "1's complement",
            "2's Complement",
            "3's Complement",
            "9's complement"
         ],
         "correctAnswer": 1,
         "level": 0
      },
      {
         "prompt": "Which of the following memory units communicates directly with the CPU?",
         "options": [
            "Auxiliary Memory",
            "Main Memory",
            "Secondary Memory",
            "None of the above"
         ],
         "correctAnswer": 1,
         "level": 0
      },
      {
         "prompt": "The collection of 8-bits is called as-",
         "options": ["Byte", "Nibble", "Word", "Record"],
         "correctAnswer": 0,
         "level": 0
      },
      {
         "prompt": "Which of the following registers can interact with the secondary storage",
         "options": ["PC", "MAR", "MDR", "IR"],
         "correctAnswer": 1,
         "level": 0
      },
      {
         "prompt": "In which of the following ways does the computer store its data in memory",
         "options": [
            "Hexadecimal Form",
            "Octal Form",
            "Binary Form",
            "Decimal Form"
         ],
         "correctAnswer": 2,
         "level": 0
      },
      {
         "prompt": "Which of the following is a combinational logic circuit which sends data from a single source to two or more separate destinations?",
         "options": ["Multiplexer", "Demultiplexer", "Encoder", "Decoder"],
         "correctAnswer": 1,
         "level": 0
      },
      {
         "prompt": "Which of the following is a group of bits that tells the computer to perform a particular operation?",
         "options": [
            "Accumulator",
            "Register",
            "Intruction Code",
            "None of the above"
         ],
         "correctAnswer": 2,
         "level": 0
      }
   ],
   "level1": [
      {
         "prompt": "Where is the document temporarily stored during working on a document on a PC?",
         "options": ["ROM", "CPU", "RAM", "Flash Memory"],
         "correctAnswer": 2,
         "level": 0
      },
      {
         "prompt": "Where is the decoded instruction stored?",
         "options": ["Registers", "MDR", "PC", "IR"],
         "correctAnswer": 3,
         "level": 0
      },
      {
         "prompt": "What does MMID stand for?",
         "options": [
            "Multiple Instruction Memory Data",
            " Multiple Instruction Multiple Data",
            "Memory Instruction Multiple Data",
            "Memory Information Memory Data"
         ],
         "correctAnswer": 1,
         "level": 0
      }
   ],
   "level2": [],
   "level3": [],
   "level4": []
}
